# TIMOTHY MCGOWEN

# **FULL STACK DEVELOPER**

## **SUMMARY**

The Knowledge I have gained at my various positions has given me a chance to communicate and work with a variety of people. With that experience and my natural drive to be leader and a councilor to those that need it I feel like I would be perfect for this position and be able to lend my skills to the benefit of Lambda School.

## **SKILLS**

**WEB DEVELOPMENT:** Javascript, ES6, React, Redux, HTML, CSS, SASS, LESS, NodeJS, Express, Knex, Sqlite, MongoDB, Moongoose, Photoshop, Illustrator, Adobe XD, Axios

INTERPERSONAL: Active Listener, Critical Thinking, Teamwork, Leadership, Judgement and Decision Making

## **PROJECTS**

Sauti Databank

Add description here

Celebrity: Dead or Alive

React | Axios | React Hooks | Styled Components

An application that pulls from an API of celebrity names and lets you guess if they are still alive or not, then tracks your score and displays a global score of all users.

Group Project:

- I worked on the main game logic and how to move between the large list of celebrities we were getting from our API.
- I also built out the login system that was used to keep track of individual users.

#### Bohcura: Chef Recipe Sharing

React | Axios | Redux | Styled Components | Formik

An application that lets a Chef create a Profile that will track their recipes and view the recipe of other chefs.

Group Project:

- Worked in all aspects of the app to ensure team involvement and our ability to meet the deadline.
- Set up the Redux store and actions required to do CRUD operations.
- Worked closely with other React Devs to set up the onboarding process forms and creating a unique approach to a split information gathering form.

#### Kickstarter Success - Backend

NodeJS | Express | Knex | mysqlite

An application that takes machine learning data and inputs from the user to give reliable percentages of success for a potential Kickstarter project.

Group Project:

- Created the backend using nodeJS, Express, Knex, mysqlite.
- Took data from the front end and the data machine learning API and parsed it into readable data for the users.
- Assisted in the Front End state management and the construction of the marketing site.

## **EMPLOYMENT**

## Lambda School

Team Lead - Labs · Nov. 2019 to Current, Nov. 2019 to Current · Remote

Work along side a team of six developers to help assist and direct our efforts to create an application for Sauti, a non profit that empowers cross-border traders. ( http://sautiafrica.org/our-approach )

## **EDUCATION**

Lambda School - Web Development · May 2019 to Feb. 2020

Central Arizona College · Jan. 2017 to May 2019

Associate of Arts and Sciences Web/Graphic Design 2019